ALIZA S. ABER

415-786-8704 • 473 Elizabeth St San Francisco, CA 94114 • aberaliza@gmail.com • daybreak-learning.com

EDTECH PRODUCT DESIGN & MANAGEMENT

Passionate, innovative product lead of digital educational experiences that excite and empower the learner in each of us. With over ten years directing creative and technical teams, I've honed my skills in product concepting, content scripting, UE design, and agile product/project management. Demonstrated track record of delivering successful EdTech products for audiences of all ages and for public consumers, private organizations and corporate trainings.

Areas of expertise:

- Early Childhood Product Development
- K-5 Literacy Curriculum
- Corporate Training Development
- Personal Growth EdTech
- Agile Product Management
- LMS Integration & Management
- Results & Metric Tracking
- Content Scripting
- Multimedia Product Team Management

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Decker Communications, San Francisco, CA

E-learning Project Director (Consultant)

November 2014 – Present

- Direct development of online communication course that infuses the highly reputed Decker teachings with the power of emerging technologies in webcam integration, video streaming and audio analysis.
- Build and manage project team of programmers, designers, videographers and QA, fostering their success through a collaborative and communicative management style.
- Script user experience and content through two hour video-led course with custom interactions.
- Collaborate closely with Decker staff, including company leaders who appear throughout the course video.
- Lead client and customer user tests from prototyping through beta development.
- Create and oversee project budget and development schedule.
- Consult with client on LMS integration, user testing, roll out strategy and use-tracking analysis.

Allen Interactions, Studio i, San Francisco, California

Senior Producer

January 2014 – August 2014

- Project lead for eLearning solutions that are contextual, results-oriented and highly engaging.
- Key contact for clients such as PG&E, Allstate, American Express, LinkedIn, Microsoft, and more.
- Oversaw product team including developers, designers, and multimedia production staff to develop Flash and HTML5 courses for PC, IOS, and Android.
- Pioneered user testing process for Allen Interactions and trained fellows producers in its inception.

Education.com, San Francisco, California

Instructional Designer/Content Developer (consultant)

March 2013 – December 2013

- Developed strategy for web-based gaming program that fosters student-led learning and creative expression while teaching Common Core Math and Language Arts skills.
- Designed games for users age 3-8, strategically employing limited development resources to support an immersive learning experience.
- Created matrix for topical sessions, weaving together multimedia videos, tales, games and storytelling told to support multi sensory active learning.

Pearson Foundation, Mill Valley, California

June 2012 - December 2013

Product Manager

- Led development of the new NationalMockElection.org, the nation's largest civic engagement project, in which close to two million students voted in November 2012.
- Devised social media campaigns on Pinterest, Facebook, and Twitter that increased site traffic by 30%.
- Spearheaded research with parents, teachers and students to identify ways to improve usability of WeGiveBooks.org, an interactive reading platform and philanthropic project.

volunteermatch.org, San Francisco, California

Product Manager

December 2008 - May 2012

- Conceived, designed and managed development of features and tools for nation's leading volunteerism site.
- Pioneered Agile development in the company, developing model documentation and practices.
- Interviewed and collaborated with clients, such as Google, Target, TechSoup and the Red Cross.
- Created a transformative administrative dashboard, which immediately helped users update their information and eliminate thousands of outdated opportunities clogging the database.

LeapFrog, Emeryville, California

Producer, promoted from Associate Producer March 2005

March 2003 – June 2008

- Designed and produced industry---leading learning products, including multimedia storybooks interactive DVD and electronic toys (up to 700,000 units sold per product).
- Scripted story texts, games, dialogue and songs for products, prototypes and demos.
- Defined budget, scope and schedule for entire production cycle.
- Directed art, audio, software, editing and QA teams for projects of up to one year in length.
- Fostered and managed relationships with leading educational experts and licensing partners, including Disney and Nickelodeon.
- Authored creativity---centered curriculum for new LeapFrog/Disney co---branded line.

Vista College, *Berkeley, California Essay and Creative Writing Instructor*

January 2002 – December 2002

Scholastic Publishing, New York, NY Creative Services Writer

May 1999 – September 2000

EDUCATION AND CREDENTIALS

Pragmatic Marketing Program

Product Development Certification

September 2011

New York University

Master of Journalism

December 2001

Cornell University, College of Arts and Sciences

Bachelor of Science in Children's Development (cum laude)

May 1998